Guide to the Dick Thornburgh Papers, 1932- AIS.1998.30.22
ULS Archives & Special Collections
- Awards, Gifts and Memorabilia, 1950-2007; XXII.
  - Governor of Pennsylvania, 9.
    - Award: PA Assn. for Retarded Citizens To Dick and Ginny Thornburgh:…recognizes your efforts to enhance the lives of mentally retarded citizens", February 18, 1980
    - Certificate: Borough of Huntingdon "Certificate of Appreciation….in recognition of your outstanding achievement in concluding an agreement with Amtrak to provide rail passengers service, via The Pennsylvanian with scheduled stop at Huntingdon", April 26, 1980
    - Award: International Society of Crime Prevention Practitioners, Inc. Letter of commendation…for your interest and dedication toward fostering what we consider to be the best hope we have of combating the ever increasing crime rates", May 9, 1980
    - Certificate: Appreciation from United States Coast Guard Auxiliary, May 20, 1980
    - Certificates: The Travelers Protective Association"Watch That Child Award…for participating in our child safety program", June 1, 1980 and October 19, 1981
    - Certificate: Rotary Club of Harrisburg Honorary Membership Certificate (with gold seal and ribbon) "in recognition of your outstanding career achievements during which you have exemplified adherence to the Rotary ideal of service above self", August 18, 1980
    - Certificate: National Committee for Employer Support of the Guard and Reserve "Appreciation…for your outstanding leadership, and personal support, which resulted in Pennsylvania exceeding the National Committee for Employer Support of the Guard and Reserve (UCESGR) objectives", September 13, 1980
    - Certificate: PA Retired Public School Employees Association "Appreciation…in recognition of the mature judgment, devoted labor, and unselfish dedication to the promotion of its [the Commonwealth's] welfare,", September 30, 1980
    - Certificate: Route 219 Association, Honorary member, 1980
    - Certificate: Travel PA Association, "Travel Person of the Year – 1980"
    - Proclamation: Commonwealth of PA, Pennsylvania's 300th birthday Proclaiming Charter Day [2 originals signed by the Governor], March 14, 1981
    - Award: IUP Student Government Assn, Commendation for giving time to students, and making Governor honorary member [handsome resolution], October 13, 1981
    - Award: PA Citizens for Better Libraries, "Library Citizen of the Year Award…recognition of contributions to development and improvement of library service…and passage of Act 200", October 15, 1981
    - Award: Golden Triangle Association [Pittsburgh] Oversized vellum "Golden Salute" to Richard L. Thornburgh, Governor, and entire PennDOT crews for "undertaking and completing the first phase of the Parkway East reconstruction on time. This cooperation between the public and private sectors reflects outstanding leadership…", October 28, 1981
    - Award: PA Art Education Association, Distinguished Service to Art Education …in recognition of outstanding leadership and support for visual arts education in PA", February 1982
    - Award: PA State Fish and Game Protective Association "Gold Medal Award …to Hon. Dick Thornburgh, Governor…on occasion of the Association's 100th anniversary celebration…" [Very decorative, handsome, hand letter certificate with ribbons and medal], April 8, 1982
    - Certificate: "Flight Certificate to certify that Governor Richard Thornburgh has flown in Marine One as a guest of Ronald Reagan, President of the U.S.A., signed by Presidential Helicopter Pilot, Paul S. Johnston [Decorative], May 17, 1982
    - Award: PA Travel Council, Foam backed original poem dedicated to Dick and Ginny Thornburgh and read at the First Governor's Conference, PA Travel Council, entitled: "PENNSYLVANIA", September 21, 1982
    - Certificate: U.S. Small Business AdministrationAppreciation…in recognition of his emergence as the leader among all the Governors in supporting small business….", October 6, 1982
    - Certification: Commonwealth of PA, House and Senate; Gold seal signed election results, affirming re-election of Thornburgh and Scranton [also see January 1979], January 7, 1983
    - Certificate: Commonwealth of PA, "Oath of Office… signed by Dick Thornburgh" on his inauguration day and witnessed by Samuel Roberts, Chief Justice of PA[Oversized], January 18, 1983
    - Certificate: Kid's News team 3, Scenic Hills School, Springfield, PA, Appreciation "…for your cooperation and kindness in allowing Kid's News interview…", March 15, 1983
    - Certificate: Shriners Hospitals for Crippled ChildrenMatted, gold decorated "appreciation: …for the personal interest shown in the welfare of our little patients…", April 19, 1983
    - Proclamation: Commonwealth of PA, Governor's OfficeFolder enclosed Proclamation "Philadelphia 76ers World Championship Day" signed by the Governor, with gold seal. Gold seal folder cover inscribed by the various players, June 2, 1983
    - Certificate: The Parenting Institute, Hand lettered, to Governor and Mrs. Thornburgh on National Family Day, September 19, 1983
    - Certificate: Pennsylvania Bible Society 175th Anniversary Observance Appreciation, Century IV Celebration, November 13, 1983
    - Award: PA Chiefs of Police, 1983 President's Award "in recognition of devotion to law enforcement, their community and their fellow man"
    - Certificate: Greater Latrobe School District and Senior High School Youth Traffic Safety Council …"for services rendered to its students", April 24, 1984
    - Certificate: Hempfield Area Senior High School"Appreciation… Commencement Address.", June 4, 1984
    - Award: National Association of Water Companies – PA Chapter Annual Award for Excellence [oversized, some hand lettering], June 6, 1984
    - Award: American Academy of Pediatrics citation for Outstanding Service as Advocate for Child Safety, June 1984
    - Certificates: Paul Harris Fellow: two gold emblem certificates in leather cover [Medals associated are in other boxes] "…in appreciation of tangible and significant assistance given for the furtherance of better understanding and friendly relations between the peoples of the world", June 1984
    - Certificate: Control Data Institute [Copy replaced original - mildew problem] Certificate of graduation…has complete the Control Data Institute..and hereby designated an Honorary Computer Technician", September, 1984
    - Certificate: Department of the Treasury, USA Leather folder enclosed elaborate certificate and seal of the US "…special confidence in patriotism, integrity, and diligence" of Dick Thornburgh, member U.S. Savings Bond Committee", December 12, 1984
    - Certificate: Children's Hospital, Certificate of thanks, 1984
    - Award: City of Albuquerque, Gold seal Executive Order... naming distinguished visitor Hon. Dick Thornburgh for his "…outstanding leadership in his two terms as Governor and for his contributions to the quality of life in his beloved state… and March 29 as Governor Dick Thornburgh Day", March 29, 1985
    - Award: The Franklin Institute President's Citation "...in recognition of his contributions to the support of scientific and technological development…improvement of science education…specifically the establishment of the Benjamin Franklin partnership…", April 17, 1985
    - Award: Polish Freedom Fighters Honorary Membership Citation "in recognition of outstanding patriotic leadership, extraordinary Christian heroism in the battle against communist conspiracy and contributing to the cause of Freedom and Peace", May 28, 1985
    - Certificate: City of Harrisburg, All America City Partnership Award [gold seal certificate signed by Mayor Stephen R. Reed], June 5, 1985
    - Certificate: Hogar Crea, Internacional of Puerto RicoCertificate of Recognition to Governor "for your spontaneous endorsement of the high and noble principles of our movement…humanitarian support…on behalf of the thousands of addicts who are benefiting from the services of our institution, we thank you," [colorful], March 3, 1984
    - Certificate: Commonwealth of Massachusetts, "Order of the Paul Revere Patriots"…proclaims Governor and Mrs. Richard L. Thornburgh true Paul Revere Patriots," [Oversized, colorful, gold seal, certificate signed by Governor Michael Dukakis, and noted "Dick, you are one of us! Mike"], July 10, 1985
    - Certificate: Wilkes College appreciation "…his initiation of and continued support of the cooperation between higher education and industry", Undated
    - Certificate: Punxsutawney Groundhog Club, Governor as Lifetime Member of the Club, January 22, 1986
    - Award: Congress of Russian Americans, Commemorative Medal celebrating the millennium of the conversion of Russia to Christianity to The Honorable Dick Thornburgh "…in appreciation of his efforts in promoting the cause of the Orthodox Religion…" [Oversized vellum hand lettered notable item], March 23, 1986
    - Proclamation: City of New Castle, To Governor Richard Thornburgh who has been a friend and advocate for interests which affect Western PA and New Castle, in particular….proclaim April 30, 1986 as a day in honor of Governor Richard Thornburgh "for his many contributions to the betterment of life for the citizens of New Castle and the Commonwealth of PA"
    - Award: County of Lawrence, Resolution: designating Governor Richard L. Thornburgh Day in Lawrence County "…reduced state deficit…Passage of Welfare Reform… Economic Development Strategy…recognition world-wide for the calm manner in which he dealt with the Three Mile Island nuclear plant…gratitude…", April 30, 1986
    - Award: PA Soldiers' and Sailors' Home, Erie, PAGold seal "salute" to Governor, on occasion of one hundredth anniversary "…in recognition of your outstanding efforts on behalf of PA Veterans…expressing our admiration and respect…wish you good health, success and happiness…", September 24, 1986
    - Award: Commonwealth of PA Dept. of Public Welfare: Gold seal "Citation for Meritorious Service" conferred upon Dick and Ginny Thornburgh "in appreciation for exceptional contributions to the Office of Mental Health, and to the mental health program of the Commonwealth" Signed by Secretary Walter Cohen, and Deputy Secretary for Mental Health Scott Nelson, M.D, 1979-1987
    - Certificate: National Association of Public Television Stations, "With thanks and appreciation…for your leadership in supporting vitally needed appropriations... your commitment to the use of public television… leadership that PA provide to other states…our continuing commitment to preserving and extending public television…",[Oversized hand letter vellum certificate], Undated
    - Certificate: American Water Works Association, Governor certified member of, Undated
    - Certificate: Scotland School for Veterans' Children, Scotland, PA, Gold seal certificate…Life Member of, Undated
    - Award: Corry Area High School, Special Appreciation Award…courtesy shown to the students of Corry the past seven years…", undated
    - Certificate: Eastern Regional Council on Welfare FraudCertificate…member in good standing and subscribes to promote efficient and effective means to prevent, detect, eliminate, and prosecute welfare fraud…honorary lifetime", Undated
    - Award: Yale Club of Pittsburgh, "Distinguished Alumni Award…outstanding service to the community", May 20, 1987
    - Award: Trees for Israel, Encapsulated multicolored recognition of planting of 100 trees in honor of Governor Dick Thornburgh, planted by George Kotts, undated
    - Honorary Degree: Doctor of Laws, LaSalle College, May 13, 1979 (Oversize 128)
    - Honorary Degree, Doctor of Laws, Bucknell University, June 3, 1979
    - Honorary Degree: Doctor of Laws, Gettysburg College, January 22, 1980
    - Honorary Degree: Doctor of Public Administration;Villanova University, April 15, 1980
    - Honorary Degree: Doctor of Laws, St. Francis University[Includes a framed plaque presentation of the citation], May 4, 1980
    - Honorary Degree: Doctor of Public AdministrationSusquehanna University, May 22, 1983
    - Honorary Degree: Doctor of Laws, Widener University, May 21, 1983
    - Honorary Degree: Doctor of Public Service, University of Pittsburgh [Additional smaller scroll], April 29, 1984
    - Honorary Degree: Doctor of Laws, Ursinus College [Additional citation], May 18, 1986
    - Honorary Degree: Lincoln University, Doctor of Laws, May 6, 1979 (Oversize 130)
    - Honorary Degree: Temple University, Doctor of Laws, [Citation, degree missing], May 24, 1979
    - Honorary Degree: Bucknell University, Doctor of Civil Law, June 3, 1979
    - Honorary Degree: College Misericordia, Doctor of Laws, May 3, 1980
    - Honorary Degree: Wheaton College, Doctor of Laws, May 30, 1981
    - Honorary Degree: Lafayette College, Doctor of Laws, May 30, 1982
    - Honorary Degree: Indiana University of PA, Doctor of Laws, May 14, 1983
    - Honorary Degree: Drexel University, Doctor of Laws, June 4, 1983
    - Honorary Degree: Gannon University, Doctor of Laws, May 5, 1985
    - Honorary Degree: Spring Garden College, Doctor of Laws, October 6, 1985
    - Plaque: Sibletown Project Reunion Planning Committee, Inc: Community Service Award, June 16, 1979 (Oversize 135)
    - Plaque: PA State Assoc of Township Commissioners, June 18, 1979
    - Plaque: PA Assn. of Mutual Insurance Cos: "exemplary leadership during the unique crisis resulting from TMI accident, June 19, 1979
    - Plaque: County Detectives Assn. Distinguished Public Service Award (United States Attorney, Assistant Attorney General, & Governor), [nice drawing of Governor]
    - Plaque: Main Line Chamber of Commerce, "in appreciation", October 25, 1979
    - Plaque: Carmichaels Chamber of Commerce, to Governor and Mrs. Thornburgh for visiting The Coal Region at Carmichaels, November 8, 1979
    - Plaque: U.S.S. Fairfax County, "Great Lakes Cruise", 1979
    - Plaque: USS Oliver Hazard Perry, "Great Lakes Cruise", 1979
    - Plaque: Destroyer Squadron, "Great Lakes Cruise", 1979
    - Plaque: Cartoon, Dick Thornburgh, broom in hand,"sweeping PA clean" with Father History, January 16, 1979
    - Plaque: Germantown Republican Club Lincoln Award: "…Republican who has consistently shown attributes of dedicated leadership, unswerving devotion to the betterment of mankind and a concern for the plight of common man as exemplified by Abraham Lincoln", February 12, 1979 (Oversize 136)
    - Plaque: From Rear Admiral Carl A. Brettschneider, USNR, in appreciation for strong support of the US Navy, March 13, 1979
    - Plaque: American Correctional Association, in Philadelphia, "Distinguished Service Award", August 19, 1979
    - Plaque: Concord Conferences, "Personal leadership in helping to involve new young professionals into the Republican Party", 1979
    - Plaque: "Sign," Member of BIG SHOP Homestead Works, US Steel– perhaps a sort of license plate, undated
    - Plaque: Military Affairs: PA Army and Air National Guard, "Honorary Five Star General", February 8, 1980 (Oversize 137)
    - Plaque: PA Crime Prevention Officers Association, May 13, 1980
    - Plaque: United Negro College Fund Volunteer Service Award, "…untiring efforts on behalf of higher education for minority students", October 10, 1980
    - Plaque: American Society of Mechanical Engineers, to "People of the Commonwealth of Pa", 1980
    - Plaque: Koninkluke Nederlandse, 1980
    - Plaque: Berks County Coordinating Council, Friend of Education, 1980
    - Plaque: Central Pa. Blood Bank [rescue dog image on plaque], 1980
    - Plaque: In Commemoration of the granting of the charter from the King of England to William Penn on March 14, 1681. Gavel on base "from a 300 year old William Penn Oak Tree at Longwood Gardens, Presented to Governor Richard Thornburgh," [Especially interesting], March 14, 1981 (Oversize 138)
    - Plaque: Jewish National Fund's 80th anniversary, June 10, 1981
    - Plaque: 1st Highland Watch of PA, September 1, 1981
    - Plaque: LRT Subway Ground-Breaking, Allegheny County [plaque with small shovel and subway ticket], October 19, 1981
    - Plaque: Department of Environmental Resources, Decade of Service, 1971-1981
    - Plaque: Northwest PA IYDP, International Year of Disabled Persons, 1981
    - Plaque: Celebration of PA's 300th anniversary by Cutlery Company, Bradford, PA. [Has open knife blades and shaped like PA]
    - Plaque: National Governor's Conference, by NJ State Police, 1981
    - Plaque: American Defenders of Bataan and Corregidor… acknowledge the Prisoner of War License Plates issued by PA, undated
    - Plaque: Student Advisory Board, Student Awareness Day, "in recognition of his continued support of student concerns", May 6, 1981 (Oversize 139)
    - Plaque: Scranton Long Term Care Center "…for his efforts on behalf of the elderly and disabled", September 17, 1981
    - Plaque: Pennsylvania's 300th Birthday, Athens-Sayre/ South Waverly, September 1981
    - Plaque: American Subcontractors Association of PA, "Blueprint for Progress", November 1981
    - Plaque: Lehigh Valley N-6 Rebuilt, Sayre Shop, from Valley Railroad Association, Sayre, 1981
    - Plaque: Celebration of Chanukah, Yeshiva Academy of Harrisburg, 300th Anniversary of PA
    - Plaque: Northwestern PA Chiefs of Police, "…special effort in crime prevention…", May 1981
    - Plaque: PA Association of Municipal Transportation Authorities, April 8, 1989 (Oversize 140)
    - Plaque: PA Elks State Association…for outstanding leadership, foresight, and initiative in programs that guide the youth …in worthy goals and ideals"
    - Plaque: APSCUF Special Award re creation of State System of Higher Education, SB 506, November 12, 1982
    - Plaque: Jewish War Veterans…Richard Thornburg[h missing], 1982
    - Plaque: To Dick Thornburgh "Champion of Local Government", 1982
    - Plaque: Catholic War Veterans, "Man of the Year", 1982
    - Plaque: Minority Input Committee…"your contributions to Minority Business Development", 1982
    - Plaque: Highway Builder, Spring 1982 (Oversize 141)
    - Plaque: Republican Dick Thornburgh Dinner, March 5, 1982
    - Plaque: City of Williamsport, June 11, 1982
    - Plaque: PA Cemeteries, June 1982
    - Plaque: PA Association of County Drug and alcohol Administrators, July 29, 1982
    - Plaque: Sponsor Ducks Unlimited, Misty Marsh Chapter, September 10, 1982
    - Plaque: PA School Boards Association, October 13, 1982
    - Plaque: Penn Woods, 300th PA Anniversary, December 1982
    - Plaque: Commemorative collection of PA seals
    - Plaque: Disabled Veterans, October 1, 1982
    - Plaque: Certificate Of Appreciation: Hon Dick Thornburgh "outstanding and dedicated service to all veterans" Carlisle Post 101, March 1983 (Oversize 142)
    - Plaque: Dedication of Tulio Convention Center, Dick Thornburgh Governor, Erie [Picture of building], June 7, 1983
    - Plaque: To Governor Thornburgh "Our friend in PA whose personal involvement made possible the selection of Pocono Mt. Industrial Park as new center for Charles of Ritz Group, October 20, 1983
    - Plaque: To Dick Thornburgh, Governor, in "appreciation of support of Montage All-Season Sports Area as Economic and Community Asset…Lackawanna County…", 1983
    - Plaque: To Governor Dick Thornburgh at 20th Anniversary Reception of Community College Act of 1963
    - Plaque: Poem "The Wheel" "Warped Wheel" To Ginny and Dick Thornburgh, United States Attorney 206 1-4 [?]
    - Plaque: To Dick Thornburgh, "Minister of God"…for you and your family….PA Ministers Seminar, 1982
    - Plaque: American Legion Citation of Appreciation..Gov Dick Thornburgh…outstanding service and assistance to economic well-being of veterans and goals of National Economic Commission of American Legion", 1983
    - Plaque: To Dick Thornburgh Governor, "outstanding dedication to veterans in expansion of State Veteran's Homes, Wilkes-Barre, PA, June 21, 1984 (Oversize 143)
    - Plaque: Cross Stitched Amish Buggy, Allensville, June 22, 1984
    - Plaque: Distinguished Service Award re Minority Business Development, to Dick Thornburgh, Governor, from Regional Minority Purchasing Council Central PA, September 26, 1984
    - Plaque: Pittsburgh, Red Rock & Keystone Job Corps Centers …Governor Dick Thornburgh…for support of Job Corps, October 4, 1984
    - Plaque: Wooden plaque carved with "Old Main", Geneva College, for participation in inauguration of President McFarland, October 27, 1984
    - Plaque: To Governor Dick Thornburgh from International Fellows of US Army War College, class of '84 [national eagle looking emblem on metal plate]
    - Plaque: PA League of Urban Schools…Governor Dick Thornburgh…recognition of Distinguished Contributions to PA Basic Education, March 26, 1985 (Oversize 144)
    - Plaque: Governor Dick Thornburgh…in recognition of his sympathy and support in our cause to maintain the memory of the Holocaust, by Assn. of Jewish Holocaust Survivors in Philadelphia, April 16, 1985
    - Plaque: Meritorious award…Governor Dick Thornburgh… re soil conservation, April 1985
    - Plaque: Governor Dick Thornburgh…grateful appreciation for efforts to protect our communities and our children, by PJOA [PA Juvenile Officers Assn.], September 1985
    - Plaque: PA School Boards Assn….special educational award and recognition…Governor Dick Thornburgh….leadership in "Turning the Tide" toward excellence in public Schools, October 16, 1985
    - Plaque: To Hon Dick and Ginny Thornburgh…their significant contributions and outstanding leadership in promoting delivery of community mental health and mental retardation services…PA Assn. of Community Mental Health/Mental Retardation Providers, October 18, 1985
    - Plaque: American Shaw Festival 1985 Coghlan Award to Hon Dick Thornburgh…outstanding support of and Contributions to artistic and cultural life of PA, October 18, 1985
    - Plaque: Citizens for the Arts in PA, to Governor Dick Thornburgh and Ginny Thornburgh…contributions to quality of life of all Pennsylvanians …extraordinary support and encouragement of the arts and cultural institutions, Harrisburg, October 1985
    - Plaque: Autographed photograph of submarine USS Pittsburgh SS N720, commissioned 23 Nov 85, to Governor Dick Thornburgh, Signed by Commanding Officer [two plaques]
    - Plaque: Family of the Year Award to Governor & Mrs. Thornburgh by ARC, 1985
    - Plaque: Keystone Twirlers Special Award, Hon Dick Thornburgh…appreciation for dedicated support of youth of our state, September 1985
    - Plaque: Juvenile Court Judges' Commission, "…support for the Juvenile Court and a commitment to Children and Youth" (Oversize 145)
    - Plaque: North Penn Valley Boys' Club "Honorary Board of Directors"
    - Plaque: Honorary Greyhound Driver
    - PA Seal: Pennsylvania State Governor: Hon. Richard L. Thornburgh
    - Plaque: Delta Air Lines: "…a Flying Colonel of the Delta Fleet" in support of the air transportation industry
    - Plaque: National Tom Mix Festival, DuBois, PA to "Governor Thornburg" [no "h"]
    - Plaque: Israel Chebrat-Neurim
    - Plaque: Advisory Scan, Dick Thornburgh…special guest.. text re renewing economy…
    - Plaque: Idaho Park Foundation: "…entitles holder to 1 square inch of Dollar Mountain at Elkhorn in Sun Valley, Idaho…"
    - Gifts: [to be given BY Governor: samples], Small porcelain plate with PA seal, Small "You've got a Friend in PA" lapel pin, Parker pen with Governor's signature, in box with PA seal and Governor signature (Oversize 146)
    - Gift: Silver PA Tercentenary Medal, 1681-1981, with PA Seal, From Matt Ryan, speaker of PA House of Representatives; one of a series of 400, October 5, 1981
    - Gift: Ceremonial key to Allentown, PA.
    - Gift: Scaled down heavy miniature steel beam: "USS, tapped 4-24-81, 1st Heat – 2nd Century/ Homestead Works" [See others from US Steel Homestead Works]